{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ahom and Mughal",
                "B. Mughal and Burmese",
                "C. Ahom and Burmese",
                "D. British and Burmese"
            ],
            "question": "The battle of Ghiladhari was fought between:",
            "answer": "A. Ahom and Mughal"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Koliabor",
                "B. Guwahati",
                "C. Pragjyotishpur",
                "D. Charaideo"
            ],
            "question": "In Ancient times, Assam is also known by the name of__.",
            "answer": "C. Pragjyotishpur"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Haliram Phukan",
                "B. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "C. Atmaram Sharma",
                "D. Anandaram Dhekial Phukan"
            ],
            "question": "Who was called as the 'Ram Mohan Roy' of Assam?",
            "answer": "D. Anandaram Dhekial Phukan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1977",
                "B. 1974",
                "C. 1973",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, the capital of Assam shifted from Shillong to Dispur?",
            "answer": "C. 1973"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1912",
                "B. 1917",
                "C. 1953",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The Asam Sahitya Sabha was first founded in the year __.",
            "answer": "B. 1917"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
                "B. Padmanath Gohain Baruah",
                "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
                "D. Rajanikanta Bordoloi"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first President of Asam Sahitya Sabha?",
            "answer": "B. Padmanath Gohain Baruah"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1",
                "B. 3",
                "C. 6",
                "D. 5"
            ],
            "question": "Total numbers of National Parks in Assam are __.",
            "answer": "C. 6"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 6",
                "B. 5",
                "C. 4",
                "D. 2"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of bridges over the river Brahmaputra are __.",
            "answer": "A. 6"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kalibor",
                "B. Tezpur",
                "C. Bongaigaon",
                "D. Jogighopa"
            ],
            "question": "The Naranarayan Setu connects the Pancharatna Town with which city?",
            "answer": "D. Jogighopa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pratap Singha",
                "B. Siva Singha",
                "C. Rudra Singha",
                "D. Godadhar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The post of Bar Phukan was first created by:",
            "answer": "A. Pratap Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Meghadut",
                "B. Varuna",
                "C. Vayu",
                "D. Hangsavega"
            ],
            "question": "The ambassador sent by Bhaskarvarman to Harshabardhana was:",
            "answer": "D. Hangsavega"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1932",
                "B. 1945",
                "C. 1954",
                "D. 1935"
            ],
            "question": "The first Assamese film 'Joymoti' was released in the year __.",
            "answer": "D. 1935"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 2nd May",
                "B. 3rd September",
                "C. 1st April",
                "D. 3rd July"
            ],
            "question": "The Abhiruchi Sports Day is celebrated on __.",
            "answer": "B. 3rd September"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1953",
                "B. 1946",
                "C. 1975",
                "D. 1966"
            ],
            "question": "Bhogeswar Baruah wins a medal in the ________ Asian Games.",
            "answer": "D. 1966"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Gobar Roja",
                "B. Sutanphaa",
                "C. Purandar Singha",
                "D. Jogeswar Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the last king of Ahom kingdom in Assam?",
            "answer": "C. Purandar Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1875",
                "B. 1900",
                "C. 1901",
                "D. 1826"
            ],
            "question": "The Treaty of Yandabo was signed in the year __.",
            "answer": "D. 1826"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Mirijiyori",
                "B. Bhanumati",
                "C. Podum Kunwari",
                "D. Sudharmar Upakhyan"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the first Assamese novel?",
            "answer": "B. Bhanumati"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bahi",
                "B. Jonbiri",
                "C. Surabhi",
                "D. Jonaki"
            ],
            "question": "The state anthem \"O Mur Apunar Desh\" was first published in the magazine named __.",
            "answer": "A. Bahi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1811",
                "B. 1826",
                "C. 1836",
                "D. 1846"
            ],
            "question": "The first Assamese magazine 'Orunodoi' was published in which year?",
            "answer": "D. 1846"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chandradhar Barua",
                "B. Hemchandra Goswami",
                "C. Hemchandra Barua",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The first Assamese to compile a dictionary named 'HemKosh' is __.",
            "answer": "C. Hemchandra Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Indira Goswami",
                "B. Birendra Kumar Bhattacharya",
                "C. Bhupen Hazarika",
                "D. Hemchandra Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Who is the first Assamese to received 'Jnanpith Award'?",
            "answer": "B. Birendra Kumar Bhattacharya"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Kirtan",
                "B. Gunamala",
                "C. Kaliya Daman",
                "D. Dasam"
            ],
            "question": "The smallest of all books written by shankardeva?",
            "answer": "B. Gunamala"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pushya Varman",
                "B. Mahendra Varman",
                "C. Bhaskar Varman",
                "D. Brahma Pala"
            ],
            "question": "Hiuen Tsang visited Assam during the reign of __.",
            "answer": "C. Bhaskar Varman"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1253",
                "B. 1324",
                "C. 1243",
                "D. 1352"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Sukapha established Ahom Kingdom in Charaideo?",
            "answer": "A. 1253"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 11",
                "B. 12",
                "C. 10",
                "D. 9"
            ],
            "question": "A Gaon panchayat in Assam consists of how many members:",
            "answer": "C. 10"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1934",
                "B. 1911",
                "C. 1921",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Mahatma Gandhi first visited Assam in the year__.",
            "answer": "C. 1921"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Iyaruingam",
                "B. Alakananda",
                "C. Bonphool",
                "D. Pita Putra"
            ],
            "question": "The first book to win Sahitya Akademi Award is __.",
            "answer": "C. Bonphool"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Haliram Deka",
                "B. Pranab kumar Borooah",
                "C. Anundoram Borooah",
                "D. Parul Das"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first barrister of Assam?",
            "answer": "C. Anundoram Borooah"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Barpeta",
                "B. Karbi Anglong",
                "C. Sivsagar",
                "D. Dibrugarh"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the largest district in Assam by area wise?",
            "answer": "B. Karbi Anglong"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Golaghat",
                "B. Sivsagar",
                "C. Karbi Anglong",
                "D. Dibrugarh"
            ],
            "question": "In which district, Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary is located?",
            "answer": "C. Karbi Anglong"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 2002",
                "B. 2004",
                "C. 2005",
                "D. 2007"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, National Games was held in Assam?",
            "answer": "D. 2007"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chirang",
                "B. Dibrugarh",
                "C. Kokrajhar",
                "D. Jorhat"
            ],
            "question": "Gibon Wildlife Sanctuary is located at __?",
            "answer": "D. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1970",
                "B. 1965",
                "C. 1973",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The Guwahati Tea Auction Center was established in which year?",
            "answer": "A. 1970"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dhubri",
                "B. Darrang",
                "C. Dibrugarh",
                "D. Dhemaji"
            ],
            "question": "The Malini Than is located in which district of Assam?",
            "answer": "D. Dhemaji"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Tangla",
                "B. Jagirod",
                "C. Dhuburi",
                "D. Tinsukia"
            ],
            "question": "Which city of Assam has the largest dry fish market of Asia?",
            "answer": "B. Jagirod"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1976",
                "B. 1946",
                "C. 1948",
                "D. 1963"
            ],
            "question": "Guwahati University was established in which year?",
            "answer": "C. 1948"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Krishna Kanta Handique",
                "B. Hemchandra Goswami",
                "C. Padmanath Gohain Baruah",
                "D. Rajanikanta Bordoloi"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first vice-chancellor of Guwahati University?",
            "answer": "A. Krishna Kanta Handique"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 11",
                "B. 14",
                "C. 13",
                "D. 10"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of Parliamentary constituency in Assam are __.",
            "answer": "B. 14"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1931",
                "B. 1946",
                "C. 1943",
                "D. 1948"
            ],
            "question": "Lakshminath Bezbaroa is honoured with 'Rasaraj' by Asam Sahitya Sabha in the year __.",
            "answer": "A. 1931"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Madhava Kandali",
                "B. Sankardev",
                "C. Madhabdev",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Namghosa was written by __.",
            "answer": "C. Madhabdev"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1988",
                "B. 1976",
                "C. 1934",
                "D. 1999"
            ],
            "question": "'Halodhia Choraye Baodhan Khai' won the National Film Award for Best Feature Film in the year __.",
            "answer": "A. 1988"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhabendra Nath Saikia",
                "B. Jahnu Barua",
                "C. Bhupen Hazarika",
                "D. Manju Borah"
            ],
            "question": "The film \"Halodhia Choraye Baodhan Khai\" was directed by __.",
            "answer": "B. Jahnu Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 2.09 %",
                "B. 2.50 %",
                "C. 2.39 %",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "How much percent of the Indian landmass is covered by the State of Assam?",
            "answer": "C. 2.39 %"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Assamese",
                "B. Sanskrit",
                "C. Bengali",
                "D. Brajavali"
            ],
            "question": "Which language is used by Sankardev to written Borgeets?",
            "answer": "D. Brajavali"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 72.58 %",
                "B. 73.12 %",
                "C. 72.19 %",
                "D. 73.98 %"
            ],
            "question": "The literacy rate of Assam according to 2011 census is__.",
            "answer": "C. 72.19 %"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1892",
                "B. 1899",
                "C. 1902",
                "D. 1894"
            ],
            "question": "When the uprising of Patharughat took place?",
            "answer": "D. 1894"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
                "B. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "C. Tarun Ram Phookan",
                "D. Maniram Dewan"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the President of the Swaraj Party in Assam during freedom movement?",
            "answer": "C. Tarun Ram Phookan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dhubri",
                "B. Karimganj",
                "C. Goalpara",
                "D. Dhemaji"
            ],
            "question": "The terracotta industry is located in__.",
            "answer": "A. Dhubri"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1213",
                "B. 1228",
                "C. 1243",
                "D. 1262"
            ],
            "question": "The Ahom Kingdom was established in the year__.",
            "answer": "B. 1228"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pramatta Singha",
                "B. Rudra Singha",
                "C. Purandar Singha",
                "D. Siba Singha"
            ],
            "question": "The Shiv dol was constructed during the reign of __.",
            "answer": "D. Siba Singha"
        }
    ]
}